Guide to the Stanford University Student Demonstration Audio Collection SC1080
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University student demonstration audio collection
1965-1971
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University. University Communications
SC1080
1 Linear Feet (18 audiotapes)
Audio recordings of Stanford student demonstrations, sit-ins, and Academic Senate and Council meetings.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Transferred from University Communications, 2007.
Description of the Collection
Audio recordings of Stanford student demonstrations, sit-ins, and Academic Senate and Council meetings.
Access to Collection
The materials are open for research use.
Original audiotapes are restricted. Patrons must consult use copies.
Existence and Location of Copies
The audiotapes have been digitized and are available online.
Student movements -- California -- Stanford.; Students -- Political activity.; Student demonstrations.; Pitzer, Kenneth S.; Stanford University. University Communications
- Audio recordings, Accession ARCH-2007-147
  - ASSU Council of Presidents, tape #2, 1969 Aug 8; 1.1; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
  - Sit-in, Old Union--Anti-ROTC, 1970 Apr 23; 1.2; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
  - Sit-in, Old Union--Anti-ROTC (bust announcement), 1970 Apr 23-24; 1.3; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
  - Anti-ROTC Movement, C15 Sessions, 1970 Apr 24; 1.4; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
  - Anti-ROTC movement, meeting in Memorial Auditorium, 1970 May 12; 1.5; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
  - April 3rd Movement discussion, Memorial Auditorium, reaction to Trustees decision to retain SRI, proposals for action, part 1 of 3, 1969 May 14; 1.6; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
  - April 3rd Movement meeting, Memorial Church, part 3 of 3, 1969 May 14; 1.7; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
  - Meeting of the Stanford Community, Judicial System Confrontation, Memorial Auditorium, reel 1 of 2, 1968 May 6; 1.8; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
  - Meeting of the Stanford Community, Judicial System Confrontation, Memorial Auditorium, reel 2 of 2, 1968 May 6; 1.9; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
  - Academic Senate, reel #1, 1966 May 31; 1.10; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
  - Academic Senate, reel #2, 1966 May 31; 1.10; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
  - Academic Senate, reel #4, 1966 May 31; 1.10; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
  - Academic Council, reel #2, 1966 Jun 1; 1.13; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
  - Academic Council, reel #3, 1966 Jun 1; 1.14; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
  - Academic Council, reel #5, 1966 Jun 1; 1.15; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
  - Academic Council meeting, 1970 Apr; 1.16; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
  - Panel discussion, reel #1, 1965 Oct 30; 1.17; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
  - Parents discussion, reel #2, 1965 Oct 30; 1.18; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)